YVONNE M. RUIZ

385 Grand Street, apt L1201, NY, NY 10002 www. linkedin.com/in/yvonneruiz

yvonneruizdesign.com 646.732.4523 yvesmruiz@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Designer of Prints and Textiles with a focus on womenswear, intimates/sleepwear, active/sport/ lounge, swimwear, children, home and accessories. High taste level and quality standards. Speciality in creating original artworks, compelling color stories, engineered print layouts, repeats, colorways, trend research and development. Offering a unique combination of aesthetic and digital skills. Develop trends, concepts and product through lens of customer and brand DNA.

Skills

Skilled in NedGraphics, Photoshop, Illustrator, Kaledo, Microsoft Office Strong communicator and team leader, Project Management, Product Development, Design, Analysis, Relationship Management, Project Support Fluent in Spanish, Conversational Italian

Professional Experience

Adjunct Professor, New York, NY

Jan 2021 to Present

Fashion Institute of Technology

- Teach digital knit and print design using Kaledo, NedGraphics, Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator
- Develop relevant and engaging curriculum and classroom planning for class exercises and student projects
- Use current technology including Google and Blackboard to convey course work, lectures, video tutorials and communicate with students
- Work closely with students to keenly develop designs and color work for strong, cohesive knit and print collections

Textile Designer, New York, NY

2000 to Present

Clients: Talbots, Haven, Victoria's Secret, Gap, Suzie Kondi, Salon 1884, NuPrimary, Abercrombie & Fitch, Ralph Lauren, Jones NY, Liz-Claiborne, Vera Bradley, Tommy Bahama, Isaac Mizrahi

- Design and style product lines, prints and colorways for in-house open lines and various customers; such clients include women's, men's, teen, baby, missy, swimwear and home markets
- Track and design on trend print artwork for upcoming line developments
- Work with art studios and other in-house departments on execution of original artwork, repeats, colorways and other art development needs
- Communicate with mills for screen developments, strike-offs and final fabric and color approvals
- Purchase artwork for various lines and needs from outside art studios
- Create concept and presentation boards for licensed brands, open line and potential customers

DRESSBARN, New York, NY

2018 to 2019

Director Print & Color

- Developed seasonal color palettes and prints stories, working closely with Trend and Concept
- Purchased artwork for various lines and needs from outside art studios
- Oversaw and assisted in all Print development, direction, color and sorting amongst all categories
- Led and worked closely with Print Stylists to ensure concept intentions were met
- Monitored and recognized relevant print and color trends and consumer needs
- Supported leadership vision and business needs
- Created presentation boards for seasonal concept meetings
- Led Color team; updating color palettes and reviewing strike offs and digital printing samples
- Implemented a strike off library to track, maintain and safeguard strike offs for all teams to share
- Secured prints were fabric specific within printing limitations
- Collaborated with design and merchant teams to support communication and review of print direction and development
- Spearheaded meetings with fabric and sourcing teams to ensure high quality results while hitting timelines - assisted in assessing any problems, concerns, needs from overseas mills
- Studied and understood company DNA. Tracked best vs worst sellers and communicated with team
- Overhauled and streamlined Print Department work processes
- Implemented a digital artwork archive library for easy print identification and tracking
- Tracked and managed department budget. Including; art studios, purchased artwork, CAD program, computer and printer needs, freelance budget, overall upkeep
- Refined color library and color calibrated environment to secure consistent color
- Partnered with internal IT and external vendors to keep abreast of new technologies

Mill Director, Union City, NJ

1997 to 1999

Bordo Knitting Mill - Sweaters

- Designed and styled prototypes for in-house label
- Managed development of knit programs from technical specification stage to final delivery, overseeing all production control (knit, cut, sew) while manufacturing top quality goods
- Coordinated closely with Client's production and concept designers to manufacture products that met quality fits and quality standards
- Directed quality control of first garment samples through production garments, controlling spec sheets and garment information packages

Education

Textile/Surface Design, Fashion Institute of Technology, New York, NY **Bachelor of Arts**, Spanish Literature, University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT